Andy Fernandez

Full Stack Software Engineer with 10+ years experience working with Python, JavaScript, SQL, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux and others. Work in several companies such as Ascentis, Truepill and Howdy.com. Team player, committed, responsible and focused on personal and team goals.

EXPERIENCE

Howdy.com, Montevideo — Full Stack Software Engineer

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

Work for several startups with different tech stacks, business objectives and roles. Scenario that allows me to learn how to adapt fast to different environments and start being productive and add value in short amounts of time.

Ascentis Co., Montevideo — Full Stack Software Developer

JULY 2019 - FEBRUARY 2021

Work at reporting solution developing new user interfaces with ReactJS and maintaining REST services written in Java and C# programming languages.

TourinfoSys LLC., Havana — Full Stack Software Developer

APRIL 2016 - JULY 2019

Design and develop TourinfoSys platform, Cuba VIP yacht & Cuba tours and travels websites. Worked with several technologies like Django, Flask, Angular, Java and others.

Computer Sciences University, Havana — *Database Teacher*

SEPTEMBER 2014 - APRIL 2016

Teach database systems, database tuning and advisor some thesis works oriented to data mining using association rules.

Computer Sciences University, Havana — Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2014

Design and develop some products for Cuban Customs Management System (GINA) such as Peoples Management and International Transportation Means Control.

Movile: +598 9 494 6990

Email: afgarabote@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/afgarabote

Montevideo, Uruguay

SKILLS

Frontend Development:

Angular, ReactJS, JavaScript jQuery, CSS3, HTML5, SASS

Backend Development:

Django, Flask, FastAPI, Python, Spring Boot, Java

Database Management:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Oracle

Software in General:

Linux, MacOS, Windows, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud, Git

AWARDS

Degree with honors awarded to students who have relevant results and finish studies with more than 4.75 / 5 points.

LANGUAGES

Spanish native language **English** advanced intermediate

EDUCATION

Computer Sciences University, Havana — *Software Engineer*

SEPTEMBER 2007 - SEPTEMBER 2012

Learn about software development process, agile software development methodologies, algorithms, data structures, mathematics, software engineering, networking, information technologies security, databases and others.

PROJECTS

Qubierto — The network of qastronomic collaborators

https://empresas.gubierto.com/encontrar-colaboradores

Developed using FastAPI, React, SQLAlchemy and others. Deployed in AWS using Docker, Kubernetes and deployed automatically through Github Actions. Allow companies to publish job openings and benefit from over 1k+ collaborators network.

Bisel — *Medical consultation platform.*

https://biselmed.com

Developed using Flask, Angular, SQLAlchemy, WebRTC and others. It includes an administration panel, patient and doctor personal website and mobile application.

TourinfoSys — Tourism group management platform.

https://cubaviptravel.groupdash.io

Developed using Flask, Angular, SQLAlchemy, SemanticUI and others. It includes an administration panel with documentation, featured signup wizard to configure users travel, traveler personal space and tour operator mobile application.

International T. M. Control — *Cuban Customs System (GINA)*

https://www.uci.cu/universidad/noticias/cara-cara-con-qina

Developed using Symfony, ExtJS, Doctrine, ORACLE and others. It controls the in and out operations related to international transportation means managed by Cuban customs.

People's Management — Cuban Customs System (GINA)

https://www.uci.cu/universidad/noticias/cara-cara-con-aina

Developed using Symfony, ExtJS, Doctrine, ORACLE and others. It manages the in and out people movements through Cuban immigration and customs.